Finding Aid for the The Papers of James Hampton Kirkland
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Newspaper Clippings
  - The Nashville American: “County Court About Faces: Maj. C. T. Cheek Leads Way to Reconsideration”, January 7, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - The Nashville American: “Esquire Cheek’s Courage”(editorial), January 7, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - The Nashville American: “J. J. Vertrees on Bond Issue: Corporation Within Constitutional Limitations. Cites Case of Shelby Co. Against Exposition”, January 7, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - The Nashville American: “County Atty. Says Invalid: S. N. Harwood Declares an Election Was Necessary”, January 7, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - Texas Christian Advocate: “Dr. Winton Again,” by E. E. Hoss, February 10, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - Texas Christian Advocate: “That Give-Away Bill,” by H. M. DuBose, February 10, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - Texas Christian Advocate: “Who Says the Records?” by H. M. DuBose, February 10, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “A Typographical Error”, March 10, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “The Vanderbilt Situation Again” (editorial), March 10, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “Drs. Winton and Kirkland,” by E. E. Hoss, March 10, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “How It Could Have Been Done,” by H. M. DuBose, March 10, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “Two Questions for Dr. Winton”, March 10, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “The Vanderbilt University Situation” (editorial), March 17, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “Questions and Answers,” by G. B. Winton, March 17, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “Answered Evasively,” by E. E. Hoss, March 17, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - The Nashville American: “Great Church Will Retain Him: Bishop E. R. Hendrix’s Tribute to Dr. Kirkland”, May 1, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - The Nashville American: “Board of Trust Takes Stand; Turns down Conference and Elects Its Members”, June 15, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - The Nashville American: “Proceedings of the General Conference of Methodist Episcopal Church, South”, June 16, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - New York Sun: “Church Won’t Loose Its hold: On Vanderbilt University Which Feels Hampered”, June 21, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - St. Louis Republic: “Bishop Hendrix To Go on Trial by Methodists”, June 21, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Kansas City Journal: “Bishop Hendrix To Be Cited for Trial. Will be Charged with Defiance of the Methodist Church”, June 21, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - The Commercial Appeal: “big Fight on Hendrix. May Arrest His Character. Chancellor Kirkland to be Removed from Vanderbilt”, June 21, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Nashville Tennessean: “Developments in Vanderbilt Case: Bishop Murrah Decline Election on Board of Trustees of University”, June 23, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Christian Advocate: “The Recent Action of Vanderbilt Board of Trust”, June 24, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - New York Independent: “Vanderbilt University” (editorial), June 30, 1910 (Box 24, File 9)
  - Christian Advocate: “The Action of the Vanderbilt Board,” by E. E. Hoss, July 8, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - St. Louis Christian Advocate: “the Editor and the Vanderbilt’ (editorial), August 3, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Christian Advocate: “‘Zion’s Herald’ and the Vanderbilt Question” (editorial), August 12, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - North Carolina Christian Advocate: “Letting the Cat out of the Wallet,” by Charles F. Smith (editorial), August 18, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - New Orleans Christian Advocate: “Our Educational Crisis” (editorial), August 25, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Christian Advocate: “Zion’s Herald Again” (editorial), September 9, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - The Baltimore and Richmond Christian Advocate: “The Vanderbilt Question: Injunction Obtained by Methodist Bishops”, November 3, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - The Baltimore and Richmond Christian Advocate: “A Malicious Misrepresentation” (editorial), November 3, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Wesleyan Christian Advocate: “Where the Responsibility for the Suit Rests” (editorial), November 4, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - The Baltimore and Richmond Christian Advocate: “The Resignation of Bishop Hendrix” (editorial), November 10, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Wesleyan Christian Advocate: “Annual Report of the President of Emory College”, December 23, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Wesleyan Christian Advocate: “Doctor Winton Once More,” by E. E. Hoss, December 13, 1910 (Box 24, File 10)
  - The Daily Times (Chattanooga): “Union of Schools -- Washington and Tusculum Still Separate. Chancellor Haynes Annuls the Merger”, August 3, 1911 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Christian Advocate: “The Memphis Conference,” by J. L. Weber, October 12, 1911 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Christian Advocate: “The Memphis Conference Session” (editorial), December 1, 1911 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Western Advocate: “Settlement of the Randolph- Macon Controversy” (editorial), December 7, 1911 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Christian Advocate: “The Virginia Conference,” by T. R. Reeves, December 15, 1911 (Box 24, File 10)
  - St. Louis Christian Advocate: “Lesson from the Life of Samuel Cupples. A Memorial Address Delivered in St. John’s Church, St. Louis,” by James W. Lee, January 31, 1912 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Christian Advocate: “Annual Meeting of the Board of Education”, April 12, 1912 (Box 24, File 10)
  - Petersburg Daily Index-Appeal: “On the Junior College: Prof. A. K. Davis of Petersburg Makes Address at Staunton Meeting”, September 8, 1912 (Box 24, File 10)
  - The Baltimore and Richmond Christian Advocate: “Leaves from My Notebook,” by James Cannon, Jr., January 9, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - St. Louis Christian Advocate: “Bishop McTyeire: His Experience and Plea for Denominational Education”, January 15, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - St. Louis Christian Advocate: “The Vanderbilt University (editorial), January 15, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Christian Advocate: “Argument of Mr. Charles C. Trabue in the Vanderbilt Case”, February 7, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Christian Advocate: “Argument of Judge N. E. Harris in the Vanderbilt Case”, February 14, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Christian Advocate: “Argument of Mr. Maddin in the Vanderbilt Case”, February 21, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - St. Louis Christian Advocate: “Victory! For the Church!! Vanderbilt University Is Ours!!! Conclusion of the Court”, February 26, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - St. Louis Christian Advocate: “Bishop Hoss Assailed”, February 26, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Christian Advocate: “Why Not?” (editorial), March 7, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Arkansas Democrat: A Big Man for a Big Position” (editorial) (Kirkland elected president of University of Arkansas), April 26, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - The Augusta Chronicle: “Monument to Southern Poets Beautifully presented to City in Presence of Large Gathering. Mrs. E. W. Cole’s Testimonial to Memory of Four Men Who Made the Southland’s Songs and Verse”, April 29, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Christian Advocate: “Report of the Secretary of the Board of Education”, May 9, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Nashville Banner: “Carnegie Gives Vanderbilt a Million: Medical School Beneficiary of Iron Master’s Handsome Donation”, May 31, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - The Commercial Appear: “Futrall Continues as Arkansas Head. He Will Serve University for the 1913-14 Term”, June 29, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Florida Christian Advocate: “Vanderbilt Matter: A Florida Pastor Heartily Endorses Our Bishops,” by Fred Pixton, July 17, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Midland Methodist: “John B. Ferguson on the Vanderbilt Matter”, September 17, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Texas Christian Advocate: “Carnegie Is Denounced -- The Conference of Texas Presiding Elders,” by G. S. Perkins, October 2, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Texas Christian Advocate: “Hurrah for Judge Perkins,” by J. L. Chiles, October 2, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - St. Louis Christian Advocate: Randolph-Macon Decision Compared with Vanderbilt Case, November 5, 1913 (Box 24, File 11)
  - Nashville Banner: “The Vanderbilt Matter,” by John Allison, March 31, 1914 (Box 24, File 12)
  - Presbyterian of the Saint: “The Vanderbilt University Case”, April 1, 1914 (Box 24, File 12)
  - New York Times: “Vanderbilt University Board Wins”, April 4, 1914 (Box 24, File 12)
  - Nashville Banner: “The Church and Vanderbilt University - A precedent,” by Gilby C. Kelly, May 12, 1914 (Box 24, File 12)
  - The State (Columbia, S. C.): More on Vanderbilt: Rev. J. E. Mahaffey Replies to Dr. S. A. Steele”, May 15, 1914 (Box 24, File 12)
  - Presbyterian Advance: “Important Action by Cumberland University”, January 21, 1915 (Box 24, File 12)
  - Christian Advocate: “An End and a Beginning” (editorial), March 5, 1915 (Box 24, File 12)
  - Christian Advocate: “Who Dissolved the Contract?” by J. E. Mahaffey, April 23, 1915 (Box 24, File 12)
  - Christian Advocate: “Annual Meeting of the Board of Missions”, May 21, 1915 (Box 24, File 12)
  - Christian Advocate: “Salem -- II,” by S. A. Steele, September 17, 1915 (Box 24, File 12)
  - 1919: “Revolts Called Great U. S. Peril”, March 24 (Box 24, File 12)
  - New York Sun and Herald: “Estate Willed to 3 Children by Vanderbilt”, August 28, 1920 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Baptist and Reflector: “Christian Education,” by Harry Clark, March 17, 1921 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Nashville Tennessean: “Group of Students Here Attacks U.S. Policies in China”, March 30, 1927 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Nashville Tennessean: “Garden Notes in and about Nashville”, September 9, 1928 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Nashville Tennessean: “V. U. Chancellor Shows Iris Types”, May 7, 1929 (Box 24, File 13)
  - New York Times: “Giant Wild Irises Found in Louisiana. Plants 7 Feet High Discovered in Swamps of Mississippi Delta by New York Man”, October 30, 1930 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Nashville Tennessean: “Governor Bilbo Assailed by Members of School Group Meeting in Atlanta”, December 5, 1930 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Christian Advocate: “Wesley Hall Corner Stone Laying Fifty Years Ago”, March 11, 1932 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Nashville Banner: Article about J. H. Kirkland and his Irises (untitled), March 20, 1932 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Nashville Banner: “chancellor Kirkland Begins Fortieth Year as Vanderbilt Head -- Achievements Reviewed,” by Ben West, October 9, 1932 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Nashville Banner: “Urges Thought in Selection of Plot and Combinations for Flower Garden,” by Katherine P. Wright, March 9, 1933 (Box 24, File 13)
  - The Birmingham Age-Herald: “The Answer to Dayton”, June 10, 1933 (Box 24, File 13)
  - The Atlanta Journal: “Chancellor Kirkland’s Work”, June 12, 1933 (Box 24, File 13)
  - “Kirkland Quiets Resignation Rumors”, June 23, 1934 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Nashville Banner: “Big Donation is Received by Vanderbilt. School of Religion is Given $150,000 by Fred W. Vanderbilt, Kirkland Announces”, December 30, 1934 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Nashville Banner Magazine: “A Hobby, an Idea, and a Festival, ” by Ridley Wills, April 28, 1935 (Box 24, File 13)
  - Nashville Tennessean: “Nashvillians in Pen and Ink” (J. H. Kirkland) by Jack Moranz, October 28, 1936 (Box 24, File 14)
  - The State: “Fifty Years at Vanderbilt”, December 11, 1936 (Box 24, File 14)
  - The Richmond Times Dispatch: “Value of Small Colleges”, February 4, 1937 (Box 24, File 14)
  - The Richmond Times Dispatch: “Chancellor Kirkland Retires”, February 4, 1937 (Box 24, File 14)
  - The Chattanooga Times: “Dr. Kirkland Retire”, February 6, 1937 (Box 24, File 14)
  - The State: “Chancellor Kirkland”, February 6, 1937 (Box 24, File 14)
  - The Atlanta Journal: “Chancellor Kirkland”, February 7, 1937 (Box 24, File 14)
  - Nashville Banner: “Vanderbilt Woman’s Club Honors Chancellor and Mrs. Kirkland”, May 20, 1937 (Box 24, File 14)
  - Christian Advocate: “Dr. Kirkland Retires”, June 18, 1937 (Box 24, File 14)
  - Times: “‘Chance’ Out”, June 21, 1937 (Box 24, File 14)
  - New York Daily News: “Dr. James H. Kirkland -- Chancellor of Vanderbilt University”, August 6, 1939 (Box 24, File 15)
  - New York Journal American: “Dr. James H. Kirkland, Educator Dies”, August 6, 1939 (Box 24, File 15)
  - New York Times: “J. H. Kirkland Dies, Retired Educator”, August 6, 1939 (Box 24, File 15)
  - New York Tribune: “Dr. Kirkland Dies. 45 Years at Vanderbilt”, August 6, 1939 (Box 24, File 15)
  - The Vanderbilt Hustler: “Impressive Memorial Services Planned to Honor Kirkland”, October 20, 1939 (Box 24, File 15)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Careful Craftsmanship Mims’ Biography of Chancellor Kirkland inaugurates Vanderbilt University Press”, December 11, 1940 (Box 24, File 15)
  - The Birmingham News -- Age-Herald: “Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt Lives in This Book,” by M. C. Huntley, February 2, 1941 (Box 24, File 15)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Mrs. Kirkland’s Funeral to be Held Friday”, November 23, 1950 (Box 24, File 15)
  - Vanderbilt University - Faculty, Students, Athletics, etc. (undated) (Box 24, File 16)
  - Colleges and Institutions (undated) (Box 24, File 17)
  - Offers to James H. Kirkland from Other Universities (undated) (Box 24, File 18)
  - Poems and Humors (undated) (Box 24, File 19)
  - Iris (undated) (Box 24, File 20)
  - Kirkland’s Retirement (in 1937) and His Death (in 1939) (undated) (Box 24, File 21)
  - Vanderbilt vs. Church, 1905 - 1914 (1) (undated) (Box 24, File 22)
  - Vanderbilt vs. Church, 1905 - 1914 (2) (undated) (Box 24, File 23)
  - Vanderbilt vs. Church, 1905 - 1914 (3) (undated) (Box 24, File 24)
  - Vanderbilt - Peabody, 1907 - 1910 (1) (undated) (Box 24, File 25)
  - Vanderbilt - Peabody, 1907 - 1910 (2) (undated) (Box 24, File 26)
- Iris Material
  - James H. Kirkland’s Speeches on Iris “Judging the Judges,” at Nashville, Tennessee, no date; Two addresses at the Nashville Iris Association, no dates. (Box 25, File 1)
  - American Iris Society (AIS) - Programs, Minutes, Records, etc. 1932-1934 Minutes of Meeting of Committee on Awards, Chicago, November 25, 1932; Minutes of Meeting of the Board of Directors, New York, December 9, 1933; The List and the Revised List of Accredited Judges of AIS for 1934; Minutes of Meeting of the Board of Directors, New York, December 22, 1934 (Box 25, File 2)
  - American Iris Society - Programs, Minutes, Records, etc. 1935-1936 The List of Accredited Judges of AIS for 1935; 1935 Policy of Award of AIS; Program and Records of the Annual Meeting of AIS, Nashville, TN., May 2 - 3, 1935; Record and Resolution of Meeting of the Board of Directors, New York, December 21, 1935.Minutes of Meeting of the Board of Directors, Hartford, Conn., June 3, 1936; Report of the Secretary of AIS, June 2, 1936 (Box 25, File 3)
  - American Iris Society - Programs, Minutes, Records, Etc. 1937-38 A List of Award of AIR for 1937; Minutes of the Annual Meeting of AIS, Wilmington, Delaware, May 25, 1937; Minutes of Meeting of the Board of Directors, Chicago, December 10, 1937; Report of the Exhibitions Committee, November 20, 1937; Profit and Loss Statement, Dec.1, 1936 - Nov.30, 1937, May16 - Nov. 30, 1937; Report of Balloting, December 1937; Report on Membership, December 8, 1937; A List of Award of AIR for 1938; Secretary’s Report for Annual Meeting, Cincinnati, OH, May 12, 1938; Minutes of Meeting of the Board of Directors, Cincinnati, OH., May 14, 1938; Report of W. J. McKee, Vice President of AIS, May 14, 1938; Minutes of the Annual Meeting of AIS, May 14 - 15, 1938; Minutes of Meeting of the Board of Directors, Chicago, December 10, 1938; Revised Code Draft Drawn for the IRS Industry, no date. (Box 25, File 4)
  - Applications for Registrations and Permits for Nurseries (Box 25, File 5)
  - Certificates of Permits for Nursery Stock and Shipments (Box 25, File 6)
  - Iris Offerings and Order Sheets (Box 25, File 7)
  - Iris lists, tags, receipts, and bills (Box 25, File 8)
  - Price lists (Box 25, File 9)
  - Orders for Kirkland’s Iris (Box 25, File 10)
  - Iris Brochures (Box 25, File 11)
  - Year Book for Iris, 1917 (Box 25, File 12)
  - Year Book for Iris, 1928 (Box 25, File 13)
- Iris Material
  - Year Book for Iris, 1929 (Box 26, File 1)
  - Photographs (Box 26, File 2)
- Family Correspondence
  - James H. Kirkland to his mother (Virginia Lawson Galluchat Kirkland) (Box 26, File 3)
  - James H. Kirkland to his mother (Virginia Lawson Galluchat Kirkland) (Box 26, File 4)
  - James H. Kirkland to his mother (Virginia Lawson Galluchat Kirkland) (Box 26, File 5)
  - James H. Kirkland to his mother (Virginia Lawson Galluchat Kirkland) (Box 26, File 6)
  - James H. Kirkland to his mother (Virginia Lawson Galluchat Kirkland) (Box 26, File 7)
  - James H. Kirkland to his mother (Virginia Lawson Galluchat Kirkland) (Box 26, File 8)
  - James H. Kirkland to his mother (Virginia Lawson Galluchat Kirkland) (Box 26, File 9)
  - James H. Kirkland to his mother (Virginia Lawson Galluchat Kirkland) (Box 26, File 10)
  - James H. Kirkland to his mother (Virginia Lawson Galluchat Kirkland) (Box 26, File 11)
  - James H. Kirkland to his mother (Virginia Lawson Galluchat Kirkland) (Box 26, File 12)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1895 (Box 26, File 13)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1895 (Box 26, File 14)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1895 (Box 26, File 15)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1895 (Box 26, File 16)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1895 (Box 26, File 17)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1895 (Box 26, File 18)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1895 (Box 26, File 19)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1895 (Box 26, File 20)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1895 (Box 26, File 21)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1895 (Box 26, File 22)
- Family Correspondence
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1896 (Box 27, File 1)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1896 (Box 27, File 2)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1896 (Box 27, File 3)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1896 (Box 27, File 4)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1897 (Box 27, File 5)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1897 (Box 27, File 6)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1898 (Box 27, File 7)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1898 (Box 27, File 8)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1898 (Box 27, File 9)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1899 (Box 27, File 10)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1899 (Box 27, File 11)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1899 (Box 27, File 12)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1900 (Box 27, File 13)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1901 (Box 27, File 14)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1901 (Box 27, File 15)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1901 (Box 27, File 16)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1902 (Box 27, File 17)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1902 (Box 27, File 18)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1902 (Box 27, File 19)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1903 (Box 27, File 20)
- Family Correspondence
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1904 (Box 28, File 1)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1904 (Box 28, File 2)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1905 (Box 28, File 3)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1905 (Box 28, File 4)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1906 (Box 28, File 5)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1906 (Box 28, File 6)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1907 (Box 28, File 7)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1908 (Box 28, File 8)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1910 (Box 28, File 9)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1911 (Box 28, File 10)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1912 (Box 28, File 11)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1913 (Box 28, File 12)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1914 (Box 28, File 13)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1915 (Box 28, File 14)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1916 (Box 28, File 15)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1917 (Box 28, File 16)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1918 (Box 28, File 17)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1919 (Box 28, File 18)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1921 (Box 28, File 19)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1922 (Box 28, File 20)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1923 (Box 28, File 21)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1924 (Box 28, File 22)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1925 (Box 28, File 23)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1926 (Box 28, File 24)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1930 (Box 28, File 25)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1931 (Box 28, File 26)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1932 (Box 28, File 27)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1933 (Box 28, File 28)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1934 (Box 28, File 29)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1935 (Box 28, File 30)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1936 (Box 28, File 31)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1937 (Box 28, File 32)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1938 (Box 28, File 33)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), 1939 (Box 28, File 34)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 28, File 35)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 28, File 36)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 28, File 37)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 28, File 38)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 28, File 39)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 28, File 40)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 28, File 41)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 28, File 42)
- Family Correspondence
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 29, File 1)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 29, File 2)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson), Undated (Box 29, File 3)
  - James H. Kirkland to his wife (Mary Henderson) Fragments (Box 29, File 4)
  - James H. Kirkland to his daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland Meritt), 1902 - 1905 (Box 29, File 5)
  - James H. Kirkland to his daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland Meritt), 1913 - 1921 (Box 29, File 6)
  - James H. Kirkland to his daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland Meritt), 1926 - 1928 (Box 29, File 7)
  - James H. Kirkland to his daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland Meritt), 1931 - 1935 (Box 29, File 8)
  - James H. Kirkland to his daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland Meritt), 1936 - 1939 (Box 29, File 9)
  - James H. Kirkland to his daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland Meritt), Undated (Box 29, File 10)
  - James H. Kirkland to his in-laws (Mr. And Mrs. W. A. Henderson), 1895 - 1904 (Box 29, File 11)
  - James H. Kirkland to his in-laws (Mr. And Mrs. W. A. Henderson), 1888, 1891 (Box 29, File 12)
  - James H. Kirkland to his sister (Sue F. Tarboux), 1937 (Box 29, File 13)
  - James H. Kirkland to other family members (Box 29, File 14)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1895 (Box 29, File 15)